Finding Aid for the Collection of Laverne Shirley television series scripts, 1975-1986
UCLA Library Special Collections
Collection of Laverne Shirley television series scripts,
1975-1986
198
11 boxes (5.5 linear feet)
Laverne and Shirley was an American television sitcom spin-off of the popular television show Happy Days. The collection consists of 150-plus scripts from the Laverne and Shirley television series (1976-1982). Also included are a small number of scripts from the television show, All is Forgiven.
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Performing Arts Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library, Performing Arts Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Biography
Laverne and Shirley was an American television sitcom spin-off of the popular television show Happy Days. It ran from 1976 to 1983 on ABC and was rated the number one program in its second year of airing. The show followed the antics of two young women Laverne De Fazio and Shirley Feeney (portrayed by Penny Marshall and Cindy Williams, respectively) sharing an apartment in Milwaukee and working in a beer bottling company. Later on in the series, ABC changed the settings to have the women living in Burbank and working in a department store. Among the many memorable images from the show was Laverne's clothing which was always decorated with large, cursive L's. In 1979, the sitcom won an Emmy Award for Outstanding Costume Design for a Series.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of scripts from the Laverne and Shirley television show (1976-82). Included in the collection are scripts for 150-plus episodes. The scripts document the careers of writers such as Al Aidekma, Jeff Franklin, Marc Sotkin, and Chris Thompson among others. Also included are 11 scripts from the television series, All is Forgiven (1985-86).
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Genres and Forms of Material
Television scripts.
Container List
- All Is Forgiven
  - And Justice For Oliver, (10/10/1985) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    First draft script.
    Bob Rosenfarb
  - And Justice For Oliver, (10/16/1985) (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Final draft script.
  - I Can't Say No, (9/11/1985) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Ian Praiser; Howard Gewirtz
  - Matt At The Barricades, (11/7/1985) (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Joe Fisch
  - Mother's Day, (10/22/1985) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Kimberly Hill
  - No Friend Like An Ex-Friend, (1/8/1986) (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Miriam Trogdon
  - On Air Commitment, (1/21/1986) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - On Air Commitment, (1/24/1986) (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Past Perfect, (9/17/1985) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Paula Russell II, (11/7/1985) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Revised final draft script.
    Janet Leahy
  - Pilot, (5/22/1985) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Second draft script.
    Howard Gewirtz, Ian Praiser; Glen and Les Charles
  - Pilot, (9/26/1985) (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Laverne and Shirley
  - Production information for unknown episode, (no date) (Box 11, Folder 16)
    6 frame film strip (ca. 1980-82)
  - Lenny and Squiggy wardrobe plot, (no date) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 2001 - A Comedy Odyssey, (2/22/1978) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information; production information.
    Marc Sotkin; Chris Thompson
  - Airport '59, (8/16/1977) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Revised shooting script; production information; wardrobe information.
    Chris Thompson
  - Amazing Antonio, The, (2/27/1980) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information.
    Cindy Begel; Lesa Kite
  - An Affair To Forget, (12/9/1981) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Revised shooting script, wardrobe information.
    Steve Granat; Mel Sherer
  - An Affair To Forget Part One, (7/25/1977) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - An Affair To Forget Part Two, (8/2/1977) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Babaloo Mendel; Barry Lange
  - Angels of Mercy, (7/20/1976) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Bill Bickley; Michael Warren
  - Baby Show (The), (11/2/1982) (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Revised shooting script, annotated, wardrobe information.
    Judy Pioli
  - Bachelor Mothers, (9/14/1976) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled shooting script (September 13, 1976)
    Barry Rubinowitz
  - Bachelor Party, The, (1/8/1976) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Revised shooting script, wardrobe information, and piece of 35 mm film strip.
    Mark Rothman; Lowell Ganz
  - Bad Girls, (8/28/1979) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Bardwell Caper, (2/24/1981) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Dave Ketchum; Tony DiMarco
  - Beatnik Show (The), (12/11/1979) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Al Aidekman
  - Born Too Late, (12/19/1980) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Toger Garrett
  - Bowling and Razzberries, (1/16/1976) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Revised shooting script, wardrobe information, and production information.
    Marty Nadler
  - Breakin' Up And Makin' Up, (3/1/1978) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Marion Zola; Phil Foster
  - Bridal Shower, (9/1/1976) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled shooting script (August 31, 1976)
    Paula Roth; Judy Skelton
  - Broken Leg, (3/16/1981) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Bully Show, The, (9/26/1978) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bus Stop, (1/10/1978) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - But Seriously, Folks, (2/10/1981) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Jeff Franklin
  - Call Me A Taxi, (1/10/1977) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information; production information; cover labeled shooting script (Jan 7, 1977.)
    Deborah Leschin; Paula A. Roth
  - Candy Is Dandy, (11/18/1980) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Joanne Pagliaro
  - Child's Play, (4/14/1981) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Dana Olsen; Jeff Franklin
  - Chorus Line, A, (10/31/1978) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Marc Sotkin
  - Citizen Krane, (2/24/1977) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Revised shooting script; production information; wardrobe information; cover labeled shooting script (Feb 23, 1977.)
    Raymond Stiller
  - Collector, The, (1/29/1980) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Linda Segall; John Byers
  - Councilman De Fazio, (11/16/1982) (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Perry Williams; Phil Foster, Dottie Archibald
  - Crime Isn't Pretty, (2/9/1982) (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Al Aidekman; Nick LeRose
  - Daddy's Little Girl, (1/17/1977) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Revised shooting script; production information; wardrobe information; cover labeled shooting script (Jan 14, 1977.)
    Monica Johnson; Eric Cohen
  - Dance Studio, The, (2/14/1978) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Nicholas DeMarco
  - Date With Eraserhead, A, (7/18/1978) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Judy Ervin
  - Dating Game, The, (11/25/1980) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Dating Slump, (3/12/1976) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Revised shooting script and wardrobe information.
    Arthur Silver
  - Dear Future Model, (10/18/1976) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information; cover labeled shooting script.
    Barbara Robles; Judy Skelton
  - Death Row - Part 1, (8/24/1982) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Bob Perlow; Gene Braunstein
  - Death Row - Part 2, (8/31/1982) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Nick LeRose
  - Debutante Ball, The, (2/7/1978) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Judy Ervin; Paula A. Roth
  - Defective Ballet, (8/4/1982) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Defiant One (The), (9/29/1981) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Dentist, The, (12/13/1977) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Babaloo Mandel
  - Did She or Didn't She?, (2/25/1976) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Holly Mascott
  - Diner, The, (3/12/1980) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Robert Perlow
  - Dinner For Four, (11/7/1978) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Final shooting script; wardrobe information.
  - Do The Carmine, (7/28/1982) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Jay Grossman
  - Dog Day Blind Dates, (2/18/1976) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Revised shooting script wardrobe information.
    Dale McCraven
  - Drive! She Said, (7/28/1976) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled shooting script (July 27, 1976)
    Jack Winter
  - Driving Test, The, (1/17/1978) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Duke Of Squigmann, The, (2/5/1980) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Duke of Squigmann, The, (2/27/1980) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Pickup scene 108.
  - Excuse Me, May I Cut In, (9/25/1976) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Shooting script; wardrobe information; production information; cover labeled shooting script (August 31, 1976)
    Fred Fox, Jr.
  - Fakeout at the Stakeout, (3/26/1976) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Annotated revised shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled shooting script (Mar. 25, 1976).
    Deborah Leschin
  - Falter at the Altar, (1/22/1976) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Revised shooting script and production information.
  - Fashion Show (The), (7/20/1982) (Box 9, Folder 17)
    Marc Sotkin; Roger Garrett, Al Aidekman
  - Fat City Holiday, (7/31/1979) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Roger Garrett
  - Feminine Mistake, The, (1/23/1979) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Festival Part One, The, (7/25/1978) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information; production information; cover labeled final draft.
    Paula A. Roth
  - Fifth Anniversary, (3/10/1981) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Cheryl Alu; Winifred Hervey
  - Fire Show, The, (1/16/1979) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fourth Annual Talent Show, (10/16/1979) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Frank's Fling, (2/10/1977) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Revised final script; wardrobe information; cover labeled shooting script (Feb 09, 1977.)
    William J. Keenan
  - Friendly Persuasion, (10/13/1981) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Wally Dalton
  - From Suds to Stardom, (4/22/1976) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled shooting script (April 21, 1976)
    Buz Kohan
  - Ghost Story, (11/30/1982) (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Barry Bleach; Kenny Wolin
  - Good Time Girls, (8/4/1976) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled shooting draft (August 3, 1976)
    Laura Levine
  - Grand Opening, (11/11/1980) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Ruth Bennett
  - Guilty Until Proven Not Innocent, (10/30/1976) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Shooting script; call sheet; wardrobe information.
    Bob Sand; Bo Kaprall
  - Guinea Pigs, (12/10/1976) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Shooting script; wardrobe information; annotated cover.
  - Gymnast Show (The), (10/26/1982) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Monica Johnson
  - Haunted House, (2/17/1977) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Revised shooting script; production information; wardrobe information; cover labeled shooting script (Feb 16, 1977.)
    Andrew Johnson
  - Helmut Week End, (1/15/1982) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Here Today, Hair Tomorrow, (11/23/1982) (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Revised shooting script, production notes, wardrobe information.
    Susan Lindner; Ken Sagoes
  - Hi, Neighbors - Book II, (2/4/1977) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information; cover labeled shooting script (Feb 02, 1977.)
    David Lander; Michael McKean
  - High Priced Dates, (3/3/1981) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Charlotte Dobbs
  - Honeymoon Hotel, (1/26/1977) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Shooting script; wardrobe information.
  - Horse Show, The, (12/6/1977) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - How Do You Say "Are You Dead?" In German?, (4/8/1976) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled shooting script (April 7, 1976)
    Bob Brunner
  - How's Your Sister?, (12/13/1982) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - I do, I do, (2/3/1981) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Lesa Kite; Cindy Begel
  - I Do, I Don't, (11/17/1981) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - I Wonder What Became of Sal, (9/26/1981) (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Script for pick-up scenes (D) (H), wardrobe information.
    n/a
  - It Only Hurts When I Beathe, (9/22/1981) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - It's A Dog's Life, (11/21/1978) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - It's the Water, (3/4/1976) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled final draft (Mar. 1, 1976).
    Greg Strangis
  - Jinxed, (10/13/1982) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Dave Ketchum; Tony Di Marco
  - Laverne And Shirley Go To Night School, (9/6/1978) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Laverne And Shirley Meet Fabian, (9/20/1977) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Revised shooting draft script; formerly: "Those Kooky Crazy Girls"; production information; wardrobe information.
  - Laverne And Shirley Move In, (10/24/1978) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information; production information; cover labeled final shooting script.
  - Laverne's Arranged Marriage, (9/27/1977) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Revised shooting script; formerly: "That's Amore" and "Sky Is Falling"; wardrobe information.
    Emily Purdum Marshall
  - Lenny's Crush, (12/12/1978) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Life Is The Tar Pits, (11/10/1981) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Revised shooting script, wardrobe production information.
  - Lighting Man, (2/2/1982) (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Jack Lukes; Shelly Goldstein
  - Lonely At The Middle, (12/18/1976) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Look Before You Leap, (10/4/1976) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    David Duclon; Deborah Leschin
  - Lost in Spacesuits, (8/17/1982) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Love At The Window, (1/13/1981) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Malibu Mansion, (1/20/1981) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Monastery Show (The), (12/7/1982) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Revised shooting script, annotated.
    Nick LeRose; Ken Sagoes
  - Morticians, The, (10/25/1977) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Most Important Day Ever (The), (9/16/1981) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Gene Braunstein; Robert Perlow
  - Mother Knows Worst, (4/30/1976) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled shooting script (April, 29, 1976)
  - Movin In, (11/3/1981) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Terry Hart
  - Mummy's Bride (The), (7/13/1982) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Murder On The Moose Jaw Express, (1/15/1980) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Richard Rosenstock; Jack Lukes
  - Murder On The Moose Jaw Express Part Two, (1/22/1980) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Jeff Franklin; Charlotte Dobbs
  - New Year's Eve - 1960, (11/15/1977) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Night at the Awards, (9/9/1981) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Not Quite New York, (10/21/1980) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Not Quite South Of The Border, (11/20/1979) (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Deborah Leschin; Susan Seeger
  - Note Show (The), (9/21/1982) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Nun's Story, A, (1/26/1976) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Michael Warren; Bill Bickley
  - Obsacle Course, The, (1/25/1978) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Final shooting script; production information; wardrobe information.
  - Of Mice And Men, (10/19/1982) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Susan Lindner; Jack Lukes
  - Oh Come All Ye Bums, (11/14/1978) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Stephen Nathan; Paul B. Price
  - Oh Hear The Angels' Voices, (10/26/1976) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information; production information; cover labeled shooting script (Oct 25, 1976.)
    David W. Duclon
  - One Flew Over Milwaukee, (2/5/1976) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - One Heckuva Note, (8/21/1979) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Other Woman, The, (12/9/1980) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Out Out Damned Plout, (3/31/1981) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Paula Roth
  - Pact, The, (8/30/1977) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Michael Weinberger; Yvette Weinberger
  - Perfidy in Blue, (1/12/1982) (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Laurie Gelman
  - Playboy Show (The), (9/8/1982) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Joan Markis; Ed Solomon
  - Playing Hookey, (11/9/1976) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information; cover labeled shooting script (Nov 08, 1976.)
  - Playing The Roxy, (8/29/1978) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Please Don't Eat The Buzzards, (9/14/1982) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Andy Goldberg; Cheryl Alu
  - Prop Newspaper, (no date) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Prop newspaper dated 1981.
  - Quiz Show, The, (8/15/1978) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Right To Light, The, (1/8/1980) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Kenny Rich
  - Road To Burbank, The, (12/16/1980) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Robbery, The, (8/22/1978) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Robot Lawsuit, The, (9/13/1977) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Revised shooting script; formerly: "Babes In Toyland"; production information; wardrobe information.
  - Rock And Roll Show (The), (11/9/1982) (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Jill Gordon
  - Rocky Ragu, (12/2/1981) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Albert Goodman
  - Second (Almost) Annual Shotz Talent Show, The, (12/20/1977) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Separate Tables, (3/5/1980) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Deborah Raznick; Ria Nepus
  - Shirley's Operation, (10/18/1977) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Revised shooting script; formerly: "All I Have To Fear Is Pain Itself"; wardrobe information; production information.
    Duclon, Dave
  - Short on Time, (10/5/1982) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Revised shooting script, wardrobe information
    Jack Lukes
  - Shotgun Wedding Part Two, The, (8/7/1979) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Sing, Sing, Sing, (3/7/1981) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Ria Nepus; Deborah Raznick
  - Sirley And The Older Man, (2/21/1979) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Barry Ruvinowitz
  - Ski Show (The), (1/19/1982) (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Judy Pioli; Marc Sotkin
  - Slow Child, The, (11/8/1977) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Dan E. Weisburd
  - Society Party, The, (12/26/1975) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Shooting script and wardrobe information.
  - Some Enchanted Earring, (10/6/1981) (Box 8, Folder 16)
    David Lerner; Bruce Ferber
  - Squiggy In Love, (2/6/1979) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Stakeout, The, (10/4/1977) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Revised shooting script; formerly: "Junior G-Women"; wardrobe information.
  - Star Peepers, (12/22/1981) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Larry Levinson; Barry O'Brien
  - Steppin' Out, (9/20/1976) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Shooting script.
  - Stepping Out, (9/21/1976) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information with cover labeled shooting script (September 20, 1976)
  - Studio City, (11/4/1980) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Richard Rosenstock
  - Supermarket Sweep, (1/9/1979) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Ron Leavitt
  - Survival Test, The, (2/20/1980) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Richard Gurman; Alan Aidekman
  - Tag Team Wrestling, (8/23/1977) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Take My Plants - Please!, (7/19/1977) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Revised shooting draft script; production information; wardrobe information.
  - Take Two They're Small, (11/12/1979) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Judy Pioli Ervin; Paula A. Roth
  - Teenage Lust, (10/20/1981) (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Dana Olsen
  - Tenants Are Revolting, The, (2/13/1979) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Revised shooting script; wardrobe information; pencil sketches.
    Rob Harris
  - Testing, Testing, (10/9/1979) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Chris Thompson; Kenny Rich
  - That's Entertainment, (1/20/1982) (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Etan McElroy; Larry Strawther
  - There's A Spy In My Beer, (2/28/1979) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Julie Mishkin
  - Third Annual Shotz Talent Show, The, (12/19/1978) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - To Tell the Truth, (1/27/1981) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Two Of Our Weirdos Are Missing, (8/25/1976) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Second revised shooting script; wardrobe information.
    Bo Kaprall; Bob Sand
  - Upstairs, Downstairs, (7/24/1979) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Visit To The Cemetary, A, (10/18/1978) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Deborah Leschin; David W. Duclon
  - Watch The Fur Fly, (12/15/1981) (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Bob Howard
  - Wedding (The), (9/18/1979) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Welcome To Burbank, (10/28/1980) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - We're In The Army Now, (10/23/1979) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - We're In The Army Still, Part 2, (10/30/1979) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Judy Pioli Ervin
  - What To Do With A Drunken Sailor, (9/11/1979) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Chris Thompson; Gary Miller
  - Whatever Happened To The Class of '56?, (11/24/1981) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Who's Poppa?, (12/5/1978) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Why Did The Fireman...?, (12/18/1979) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Window On Main Street, (7/2/1982) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - You Oughta Be In Pictures, (12/4/1979) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - You've Pushed Me Too Far, (9/25/1979) (Box 6, Folder 4)